(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T17:26:29.547635",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
バンダイスピリッツより、ホロライブEXPO 2025の会場にある特設ブースで展示中の商品をご紹介！
From Bandai Spirits, here are the products on display at the special booth at hololive EXPO 2025!
ホロライブ一番くじ
Hololive Ichiban Kuji
2025年限定の一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中！
2025 limited Ichiban Kuji special photo booths are now open!
モニターをタッチしてくじ券をめくり、
Touch the monitor to flip a lottery ticket,
出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます！
and take a photo with the design that appears!
hololive 5th fes.で歌われた名曲
The hit song from hololive 5th fes.
『The Last Frontier』からなんと！
from "The Last Frontier" is getting...
フィギュア化決定！
an official scale figure adaptation!
あの感動をもう一度…旅立つ歌を…
Relive that emotion once more... with a song of departure...
フリューから「ホロライブ」プライズが全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
FuRyu's "Hololive" prizes are rolling out in amusement facilities nationwide!
4月からは新たにひっかけフィギュアも登場！
New dangling figures arrive in April!
Pick from 90 hololive and HOLOSTARS talents.
PRE-ORDER NOW!
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
Providing the most convenient payment service during your trip to Taiwan.
歌いたい曲が入っていなかった…
The song you wanted to sing wasn't there...
だったらJOYSOUND X1で歌おうぜ！
Then let's sing on JOYSOUND X1!
JOYSOUND X1 オンレマ
JOYSOUND X1 On-Demand
曲数No.1
No. 1 in song selection
AIが採点・絶賛
AI scoring and praise
曲数No.1 歌いたい曲があるって最高 JOYSOUND X1
No. 1 song count, having the song you want to sing is the best! JOYSOUND X1
バンダイ、バンダイスピリッツより、ホロライブEXPO 2025の会場にある
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits, at the special booth at the Hololive EXPO 2025 venue,
特設ブースで展示中の商品をご紹介！
we introduce the products on display!
ホロライブEXPO 2025限定の 一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中！
Hololive Expo 2025 Exclusive Special Photo Booth Now Open!
モニターをタッチして、おみくじをめくり 出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます！
Touch the monitor to flip through fortunes and snap a photo with the design!
The Last Frontierから なんと！
And from The Last Frontier...
フィギュア化決定！
figure adaptation decided!
あの感動をもう一度…
Relive that emotion once more...
スケールフィギュア化決定！
Scale figure adaptation confirmed!
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが 全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
FURYU's Hololive prizes are rolling out in amusement facilities nationwide!
4月からは新たにひっかけフィギュアも登場！
Starting in April, hook figures will also be introduced!
Pick from 90 hololive and HOLOSTARS talents!
PRE-ORDER NOW!
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
Providing the most convenient payment service during your trip to Taiwan.
新商品まもなく登場！
New products coming soon!
歌いたい曲が入っていなかった
Couldn't find the song you wanted to sing?
JOYSOUND X1で歌おうぜ！
Sing it on JOYSOUND X1!
歌いたい曲があるって最高！
It's the best to have the song you want to sing!
超特大ぬいぐるみブランド どきゅーと から商品化決定！
From the giant plush brand DOQUTE, product release confirmed!
約100cmサイズぬいぐるみニ！
As a giant approx. 100cm plushie!
タイトーブースにてサンプル展示中！
Sample on display in the Taito booth!
グルーヴコースター最新作に 白上フブキと
The latest Groove Coaster game features White Kami Fubuki and...
さくらみこがキャラクターボイスで参戦！
Sakura Miko appears with her character voice!
人気曲や、私たちが歌う曲も楽しめる！
Enjoy popular songs and even songs sung by us!
駆け抜けよう ミライのGrooveを！
Let's navigate through the future of Groove!
コラボイベント実施中！
Collaboration event underway!
ゲームのオアシスに飛び込め！
Dive into the gaming oasis!
フィギュア化決定！
Figure adaptation confirmed!
3月8日(土)予約開始!!
Reservation start on March 8th (Sat)!
1/7スケールフィギュア 予約受付中
1/7 scale figure, reservations currently open!
新ブランド始動!!
New brand launching!
コラボカフェ・プライズ 開催決定!
Collaboration Cafe & Prize event confirmed for Summer 2025!
続報は公式XやHPをチェック!
Check official X and website for updates!
公演まもなくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上照明の点滅にご注意ください 声出し応援 OK です
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. Cheering loudly is ok.
hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony EXPO25 DAY2
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
[Attention: Notice to Visitors]
PENLIGHT COLORS ペンライトカラーズ
[Penlight Colors Chart]
あの涙が 今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us as we are now,
この心に 君の欠片があるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
ひとりじゃないから
Because I am not alone.
描いたもしもの中
Inside the "what-ifs" we drew,
目を閉じた先に
Beyond closing our eyes,
色づく景色が揺れた
A colorful scenery wavered.
立ち止まる風の街で
In the wind-swept town where we pause,
重なる花びらは
Overlapping petals are
私たちの声
Our voices.
一瞬 一瞬 捕まえるみたいに
As if capturing every fleeting moment,
もっと もっと 踏み出せたら
If we could step forward more and more...
あの涙が 今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us as we are now,
この心に 君の欠片があるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
強くなくてもいい
It's okay not to be strong,
今の祈りを もっと集め 空に放つ
Gathering our current prayers more and releasing them to the sky,
この奇跡を 僕らで輝かせるから
We will make this miracle shine together.
力が湧くから あなたでもいい 抱きしめ
Because power wells up, embracing even you,
遠い未来へと 強く願い込め
Pouring strong wishes toward a distant future,
舞い上がれ 虹の風を吹かせては
Soar high, letting the wind of rainbows blow,
理想の花びら 祈る明日の空
Petals of ideals praying in tomorrow's sky.
幾億の風を吹かせては
Letting countless winds blow,
理想の花びら 彩る明日の空
Petals of ideals coloring tomorrow's sky,
何百億の 光る星みたい
Like hundreds of billions of shining stars.
ずっと ずっと 終わらないから
Because it will never, ever end,
この笑顔が もっと強くなぎ捨めて
This smile will sweep away stronger,
今未来に この手を伸ばしていくから
As I reach out my hand into the present future,
飛び交う胸も 空を見上げよう
Let's look up at the sky with fluttering hearts.
笑い 君も 刻んでゆく
Smiling, you too will carve it into time,
次の夢も 掴みとるって約束するから
I promise we'll seize our next dream too,
踏み出す一歩から
Starting from that first step forward.
harmony 重ねた
Harmony, layered
言葉 届け
words, reach out
たどたどしく 描いては
Clumsily drawing our dreams
ぎこちない と 笑っていた
Laughing at how awkward they seemed
未来予想 あの日の続きを見よう
Let’s continue the story we envisioned that day
手と手 繋いで 風も着こなして
Hand in hand, embracing the wind
扉を 叩いて 連れてきてよ
Knocking on doors — we’ll go together
どんな こと も きっと
No matter what comes our way
一緒になら 叶えていける
If we’re together, we can make it happen
鳴りやまない 希望のベル ほら
The bell of hope keeps ringing — listen
聞こえてる 歌, ah
Can you hear this song? ah...
harmony 重ねた 言葉
Harmony — layered words
鮮やかな 日々の
Beyond the vivid days ahead
向こう ずーっと 君と
Always with you, we’ll color
彩るよ ストーリー
this story
ハートに 結んだ 夢が
The dreams tied to our hearts
空へ 駆け抜けていく
Race toward the sky
キラメキに 乗せて あなたへ（届け）
Carried on shimmering light — let them reach you
メロディ どこまでも！
This melody — endlessly!
何気ない こと 思い出す
Recalling the little things
一人じゃないよって 深呼吸
Taking a deep breath, knowing I’m not alone
未体験 楽しむ 魔法の言葉
Embracing the unknown — that’s the magic of words
一息 ついて ふと 振り返って また 君を知って そのたびに
Pausing for a moment, looking back, learning more about you each time
ちょっと 勇気 出して 明日へと 飛び込んでいける
And with just a bit of courage, I can dive into tomorrow
降り積もる 道しるべは まだ
The path ahead is still being laid
憶えている 歌, ah
Yet I remember this song, ah...
harmony 手を伸ばしたら
Harmony — when I reach out
足跡に 虹が
A rainbow forms over our footprints
かかる きっと ハレル くちずさむ ステージ
The sky will surely clear, humming on this stage
ハートに しるした 場所へ 運ぶ 約束を 輝きに 乗せて 世界へ メロディ いつまでも！
A promise carries me forward, riding on its radiance, let it echo through the world — this melody, forever!
君と 踏み出した あの瞬間が たからものだって 胸を張る 今 歩いて 話して 走って 笑顔でゆくんだ 色あせないまま
That first step we took together, that very moment is now a treasure I hold with pride, walking, talking, playing, smiling — moving forward without fading away
混ざり合う 僕らの声 ほら 聞こえてる 歌, ah
Our voices blend together — listen, can you hear this song? ah...
harmony 重ねた 言葉 鮮やかな 日々の 向こう ずーっと 君と 彩るよ ストーリー
Harmony — layered words, beyond the vivid days ahead, always with you, we’ll color this story
そろそろトップはラミー！
It's almost time for Lamy at the top!
声出せ！行きたいかー！
Let me hear your voice! Are you ready?!
この6th fesを全力で楽しんでいきたいかー！
Are you ready to give it your all and enjoy this 6th fest?!
はいはいはい！じゃあみんな突っ立ないで！
Yeah, yeah, yeah! So everyone, don't just stand there!
ノー筋肉ノーライフ！ ノー筋肉ノーライフ！ ノー筋肉ノーライフ、ノーピザピザ！
No muscle, no life! No muscle, no life! No muscle, no life, no pizza pizza!
ノー筋肉ノーライフ！ ノー筋肉ノーライフ！
No muscle, no life! No muscle, no life!
ファイヤーとこどんでマッチョマッチョ！
With fire and guts, macho macho!
ノー筋肉ノーライフ、ノー筋肉ノーライフ、止まらせねえぜ筋肉！
No muscle, no life, no muscle, no life, nothing can stop this muscle!
止まらせねえぜ…！
Nothing can stop it...!
ノー筋肉ノーライフ、ノー筋肉ノーライフ、今日も今日とてマッチョマッチョレイ！
No muscle, no life, no muscle, no life, macho macho ray today as well!
年中無休鍛えた腕をシンボルに
With arms trained year-round as our symbol
無冠を積む目標を定める！
Setting goals to achieve greatness!
負けるな！超えていけ！
Don't lose! Surpass it!
こなしてルミナミ！
Get through it, Luminami!
ガチポコ手を叩け！音頭とこ足鳴らせ！
Clap your hands hard! Stamp your feet to the rhythm!
とにかく追い込めたし切れて限界まで！
Push yourself to the absolute limit anyway!
ルキもきなみ、パキパキでバリスも持ってるぜ！
Ruki and Kinami are shredded and stacked!
ほらね祝福のパワーを回してトレーニング！見捨てないで出して！
See, circulate the blessing power and train! Don't abandon it, bring it out!
見だければ光るダイヤも！
Even diamonds shine if you look at them!
やれんの？とまそう、とまらないワッツアップ！
Can you do it? Let's stop, unstoppable what's up!
なりたい！なりたい！なりたいの！
I want to be! I want to be! I want to be!
理想の身体になりたいの！
I want to have an ideal body!
わがままボディに酔いしれル！
Intoxicated by this selfish body!
夢の中までご褒美レッスン！
A reward lesson even in my dreams!
お疲れ様！今日も頑張ってるね！
Good job! You're working hard today too!
やる気がー？よろしい！えらいえらいっ！
Is your motivation... good! Great job, great job!
さあ、ここから一緒にみんなもトレーニングやってくれるかな？
Now, from here on, will everyone do training together with me?
足を肩幅に開いて、手を前にして！
Spread your feet shoulder-width apart, put your hands forward!
しわかりパンプアップ！はじまるよーっ！
Shiwakari pump up! It's starting!
バリバリバリバリ…最終ゴング！
Bari-bari-bari-bari... The final gong!
あれでしわかり、今日もあやつるかのごとく上下左右に体を動かすことにより、肉体もいたるところに祝福パワーを求めていく、お尻できる超！製産的なトレーニングなのだ！
Wonderful! By moving your body up and down, left and right, your physical body seeks blessing power everywhere, making it a super productive glute-building training!
銀色の空が割れるのを 僕は突っ立ってボーっと見ていた
The silver sky was splitting, I was standing there staring blankly
退屈に殺されるくらいなら 死んじまう方がずっとマシさ
If being bored is worse, it's much better to die
少年よ聞いてくれ 人間なんてたいしたもんじゃないさ
Hey boy, listen to me, humans aren't all that great
明日なんてもういらないから 握った拳を隠すなよ
I don't need tomorrow anymore, so don't hide your clenched fist
不安に夢を売りとばすほど まだ老いぼれちゃいないだろ
You're not old enough yet to sell your dreams to anxiety
少年よ 心の銃の引き金を引けるのは君だけさ
Hey boy, you're the only one who can pull the trigger of your heart
すべての若者は言った 僕の心を切り裂けよ
All the youths said, tear my heart apart
諦めちまった奴には 関係ない話なんだ
For those who have given up, it's a story that doesn't concern them
すべての若者は言った 僕ら叫んだこの声は
All the youths said, this voice we shouted
ベッドの下に密かに潜んでた自由さ
Was the freedom hidden under the bed
やる気のないしょうもない日々で わくわくしたいんだ
I want to feel excited in these dreary, unmotivated days
ノーキング・ノーライフ・ノーフェニックス・ノーライフ
No king, no life, no phoenix, no life
ノーキングピン・ノーピン ノーキングピン・ノーピン
No kingpin, no pin, no kingpin, no pin
ノーキング・ノーライフ・ノーフェニックス・ノーライフ
No king, no life, no phoenix, no life
おとなも子供ももっともっと yei!
Adults and kids alike, even more, yeah!
ノーキング・ノーライフ・ノーフェニックス・ノーライフ
No king, no life, no phoenix, no life
やる気元気大好き!
Motivation, energy, I love it!
ノーキング・ノーライフ・ノーフェニックス・ノーライフ
No king, no life, no phoenix, no life
頑張る君ともっともっと yei!
Working hard with you, even more, yeah!
ノーキング・ノーライフ・ノーフェニックス・ノーライフ
No king, no life, no phoenix, no life
おとなも子供ももっともっと yei!
Adults and kids alike, even more, yeah!
いつだって今だって 僕らはちゃんと実を結んで 今だって飛び立っていくんだ
Always, right now, too, we bear fruit properly and take flight right now
傷つけて傷ついたって 明日は笑ってたいな 間違いもいつかのための正解でしょ
Even if we hurt and get hurt, I want to smile tomorrow. Mistakes are the correct answers for someday, right?
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ行くんだ
Even if we fall, even if we cry, being clumsy is fine. Come on, let's go!
見慣れたこの世界で 繰り返していくだけの毎日 言えずにいた言葉を
In this familiar world, everyday just repeating itself, the words I couldn't say
風に乗せて一人つぶやいた 素直になるためには
I whispered alone, carried by the wind. To become honest with myself,
まだまだ勇気が足りないけど 水しぶき上げて飛び込んだ
I still lack courage, but I splashed the water and dove in
目を滑らせながら アクセン更に虹を描いて 青く塗り潰した
Sliding my eyes, pressing the accelerator further, drawing a rainbow and painting it blue
扉開けて飛び出そうよ 初めての未来へ
Open the door and leap out, toward a brand-new future!
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ 傷つけて傷ついたって
No matter how far, we will keep running through. Even if we hurt and get hurt,
明日は笑ってたいな 間違いもいつかのための正解でしょ
I want to smile tomorrow. Mistakes are the correct answers for someday, right?
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ行くんだ
Even if we fall, even if we cry, being clumsy is fine. Come on, let's go!
顔を上げて走り出そう 一人ぼっちが二人で
Lift your face and start running, from being all alone to being two together
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ行くんだ
Even if we fall, even if we cry, being clumsy is fine. Come on, let's go!
見たことない世界未知の世界かも 時々わからなくなって
A world you've never seen, maybe an unknown world. Sometimes I get confused
涙こらえながら 答えを探し続けてたんだ
Holding back my tears, I kept searching for the answer
溢れた涙見つけた笑顔 全部宝箱にしまって
The overflowing tears, the smiles I found, storing them all in a treasure box
いつか立ち止まったら 思い出してまた笑いたいな
If I ever stop in the future, I want to remember and smile again
満天の星空を描いて 願い事をしよう
Drawing a starry sky, let's make a wish
流れ星の鍵さえそう 僕次第で変われるんだ
Even the key to a shooting star changes depending on me
いつまでもこの日々が続くといいな 望んだって叶わないことだらけ
I hope these days will last forever. Even if I wish, so many things don't come true
でも歩けないな 明日へとこの歌が届くといいな
But I can't just stop walking. I hope this song reaches tomorrow
手をとって笑い合って ありのままを描いていくんだ
Holding hands, laughing together, drawing things just as they are
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ 傷つけて傷ついたって
No matter how far, we will keep running through. Even if we hurt and get hurt,
明日は笑ってたいな 間違いもいつかのための正解でしょ
I want to smile tomorrow. Mistakes are the correct answers for someday, right?
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ行くんだ
Even if we fall, even if we cry, being clumsy is fine. Come on, let's go!
顔を上げて走り出そう 一人ぼっちが二人で
Lift your face and start running, from being all alone to being two together
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ行くんだ
Even if we fall, even if we cry, being clumsy is fine. Come on, let's go!
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ
No matter how far, we will keep running through.
きっと未来は色に溢れ
Surely the future overflows with color,
まだ見ぬ世界をカラフルに染める
dyeing the yet-unseen world in full color.
もっと自由に ネオンの光から
More freely, hey, from the neon lights,
ずっと ずっと ずっと 夢見てるの
always, always, always, I've been dreaming.
空に光る星のように
Like stars shining in the sky,
輝きたいと願う夜
nights when I wish to shine.
広い世界に存在を証明したくて
Wanting to prove my existence in this vast world,
出来ないことばっか数えても
even if I only count what I cannot do,
胸が苦しくなるだけでしょう
it only makes my heart ache, doesn't it?
私だって絶対あの日の夢のようになれるはず
I'm sure I too can become just like the dream of that day.
響く 音色の 中 ほら 見知らぬ 景色
In the echoing tones, look, an unfamiliar scenery,
感じてたのに 近くにかがやいていたんだ
though I felt it, it was shining right beside me.
そっとのばしたこの手先 届きそうだ 想像を越える
Gently extending my fingertips, it feels within reach, surpassing imagination.
きっと見つける 私の色 ずっと ずっと ずっと 追いかけるの
I will surely find my own color, always, always, always chasing after it.
限りなく透明だった 瞳に映るすべて
Everything reflected in eyes that were infinitely transparent,
変わりゆく世界の リズムにのって モノクロを染めていく
riding the rhythm of a changing world, dyeing the monochrome.
閉じ込めなくてもいいの
It's okay not to lock it away,
不安感じても
even if you feel anxious.
私だけの 色で 描こう
Let's paint it in my own colors.
きっと未来は 色に溢れ
Surely the future overflows with color,
まだ見ぬ世界は カラフルに染まる
dyeing the yet-unseen world in full color.
もっと自由に 羽ばたくだから
So spreading my wings more freely,
ずっと あの日感じたままに
always, just as I felt that day.
そっとのばしたこの手先 届きそうだ 想像を越える
Gently extending my fingertips, it feels within reach, surpassing imagination.
やっと見つけた 私の色 ずっと ずっと ずっと 描いていくの
I finally found my own color, always, always, always painting it on.
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
歌え騒げ 宴は続く
Sing and make noise, the banquet continues,
前鬼後鬼もケダモノ！
Zenki, Goki, and beasts too!
いけないっ！
Oh no!
早歩きが来たぞ！
Walking fast is here!
たくさん殺してね
Take down lots of them,
行くよ！
let's go!
せーの 鬼・狐・狸・神社ー！
Ready, set—oni, fox, tanuki, shrine!
一歩見えて七変化
Glimpsed in a single step, changing forms,
今宵集うインターネット
gathering tonight on the internet.
お仕事に立ち上がれ
Stand up for your work,
ここはまるで湯気ん狂
this place is practically a steam wonderland.
一斉ので でゅい でゅい でゅい！
All together now, dyui dyui dyui!
月夜に隠れ潜みたく
Wanting to hide and lurk in the moonlight,
どっちでもいい よい よい よい！
either way is fine, yoi yoi yoi!
わが道を行け
Go your own way!
ゆらゆらに恋に焦がれ
Swaying, yearning in love,
切なさも揺るがぬ思いは 無駄じゃないけど
even this heartache, unshakeable feelings are not in vain, but...
祈らせて 先乱れよ
Let me pray, bloom wildly!
お暇もその旅路へ
Farewell to that journey as well,
いのらせて 先乱れよ
let me pray, bloom wildly,
お暇もその旅路へ おいでまきすねいる
farewell to that journey, come on, Oimekisuneiru!
宵の口を
At the edge of dusk,
命は短し
life is brief,
恋せよ乙女
fall in love, maidens!
しゃなりに来たね
You've come so gracefully,
一期に捧げ百花繚乱
devoting everything to a hundred blooming flowers.
千客万来おいでませ
Welcome, one and all!
暴れお祭りじゃ 打ちまくれ
It's a wild festival, strike away!
歌え騒げ 宴は続く 前鬼もダンス
Sing and dance, the party continues, Zenki dances too!
痛いことがあってもいいよ
Even if it hurts, it's alright!
やっぱり鬼っ娘耳可愛いよ！
As expected, demon girls' ears are so cute!
こっそり覗いてめっちゃすごい！
Peeking secretly, it's super amazing!
やっと見つけたお嬢様！
Finally found you, my lady!
ここから未来を繋いでく
Connecting the future from here,
夢は追いかけなかまでも
even if dreams are chased by companions,
世界で一番愛してる 愛してる！
loving you more than anyone in the world!
踊りましょう
Let's dance!
鬼もケモノも真っ盛りだぜ
Even demons and beasts are in full swing,
子まいの狐も宵の口を
even the stray fox, at the edge of dusk,
命は短し
life is brief,
しゃなりに来たね
you've come gracefully.
一期に捧げ百花繚乱
Devoting everything to a hundred blooming flowers,
千客万来おいでませ
welcome, one and all!
暴れお祭りじゃ 打ちまくれ
It's a wild festival, strike away!
歌え騒げ 宴は続く
Sing and dance, the party continues,
前鬼もダンス 痛いことがあってもいいよ
Zenki dances too, even if it hurts, it's alright!
色づく思いは切な百花繚乱 花吹雪
Colorful feelings are a heartbreaking blizzard of petals.
2曲目も行きますよ！みんな声出せ！
Going into the second song! Everyone, raise your voices!
パッと咲いて散った
Bloomed in a flash and scattered,
花は終わりを告げてくその時を
the flowers announce their end at that moment.
待てど暮らせどを告げすまず
Waiting and living without telling...
そっと触れて知った
Gently touched and learned
胸の内の温かさを 初めてのこの気持ちだけ抱きしめていた
the warmth within my chest, holding onto this very first feeling.
月日交わした約束は
The promises exchanged over days and months
本物だってきっと信じてる
I surely believe they are real.
色はにほへと の花に見せられた少女たち
Maidens enchanted by the flower of "Irohanihoheto",
ああ はらり はらり 落ちる花をまとい踊れ
ah, flutter, flutter, dance draped in falling flowers.
若やたれそでも 思いの丈を飲み込んでみた
Even with youthful sleeves, I tried swallowing down my feelings.
誰もみな焦がれる 宵の断りよ
Everyone yearns for it, the rejection of the night.
色づく思いは切な百花繚乱 花吹雪
Colorful feelings are a heartbreaking blizzard of petals.
皮膚みが揃えて ここにさあおいで
Gather your skin and hair, come right here.
宵月 かわした約束は
The promise exchanged under the evening moon
本物だってきっと信じてる
I surely believe it is real.
色はにほへと の花に見せられた少女たち
Maidens enchanted by the flower of "Irohanihoheto",
ああ はらり はらり 落ちる花をまとい踊れ
ah, flutter, flutter, dance draped in falling flowers.
若やたれそでも 思いの丈を飲み込んでみた
Even with youthful sleeves, I tried swallowing down my feelings.
誰もみな焦がれる 宵の断りよ
Everyone yearns for it, the rejection of the night.
色づく思いは切な百花繚乱 花吹雪
Colorful feelings are a heartbreaking blizzard of petals.
風にはる 音目の順序 さあ起これ
Spring breeze, order of sounds, arise now!
自由自由！
Free, free!
あ、ご挨拶 ご挨拶。はい、まずあやめから！どうぞ！
Ah, greetings, greetings. First, Ayame! Go ahead!
はい、みんな！いろはにほへとあやふみのアヤ・トントン・ナキリ・アヤメだよー！
Hi everyone! I'm Ayatonton Nakiri Ayame of Irohanihoheto Ayafumi!
そして？
And next?
はい！いろはにほへとあやふみのふぶきんと白上フブキです！
Hi! I'm Fubuking Shirakami Fubuki of Irohanihoheto Ayafumi!
そして？
And next?
はい！いろはにほへとあやふみのミータンと大神ミオでーす！
Hi! I'm Metan Ookami Mio of Irohanihoheto Ayafumi!
そして、３人揃って……！
And all three of us together...
いろはにほへとあやふみでーす！
We are Irohanihoheto Ayafumi!
ちょっとちょっと何かあやふみで踊るの久しぶりじゃないですか！
Wait, isn't this the first time in a while we're dancing as Ayafumi?!
さあさあさあよ！
Now, now, now!
よかった！
That was great!
はぁー、ちょっとね、なんか気持ちよかった。
Phew, I feel so refreshed.
よかった！
That was great!
ね、ちょっとさ
Right? You know,
百鬼あやめおらんさ、
Nakiri Ayame, you see—
ちょっとさ、ちょっとあの裏話になってしまうんですけど、ま、曲越えてメドレーにしようって決めたじゃないですか。
This is a bit of a behind-the-scenes story, but we decided to make it a medley across songs, right?
百鬼あやめの振り付け覚えてる？って
And she asked, "Do you remember Ayame's choreography?"
色づく想いまって
Thinking of "Irozuku Omoi"
練習のときちょっと焦ったよね。そうそうそう
we panicked a bit during rehearsal. Yeah, exactly.
えーっと、みたいな。
Like, "Uh, wait a minute..."
あ、これの、そうそうそう。右か左か忘れちゃうから。
Ah, right, right. We kept forgetting whether it was right or left.
あと順番ね！順番こう、これね。
And the order! The order goes like this.
猫マシーンやって、うわあ！で
Neko mascot pose, yeah! And then—
でもさ、でも久しぶりにこれができたよね？全部分かってた。
But you know what? We managed to pull it off after so long, right? We remembered all of it.
これね、もうめちゃめちゃ楽しくけらさせていただきました。
This was honestly super fun, we had an absolute blast!
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much!
さてね、とうとう皆さんフェスも最後、ステージ3でございます！
Now then, everyone, this is finally the final stage of the fes, Stage 3!
え、ステージ3なんですか？
Eh? Stage 3?
そうでございます。あ、てことは、ステージ4があるってことですか？
That is correct. Oh, does that mean there is a Stage 4?
えー！？あ、ステージ4？え、まだあるってこと？
Eh?! Stage 4? There's still more?
ないないない、何言ってんだよ。
No, no, no, what are you talking about?
ないですよもう！我々でライブは最後です！
There isn't any! We are the very last live performance!
なんですけども、ステージ3の皆だいぶ気合い入ってるので皆さんね、マジでコール負けねえように頑張ってくださいよ！
That said, everyone in Stage 3 is super pumped up, so make sure you don't lose in the call-and-response!
頑張ってー！ありがとうございます！
We'll do our best! Thank you so much!
やあ、序盤なのね、ラミーのね、バリバリバリバリやりましたね。
Man, right at the start, Lamy's song had us going baribari!
ね、バリバリからのシャバルのエモさが半端なくて、エモはだいぶ爆発中。
Right? Going from baribari to Shaba's emotional vibe was unreal, peak emotional overload.
よかったねみおもね！いやよかったよー。
That was great, Mio too! Yeah, it was wonderful.
珍しく爽やかな曲です。いやでも今回のカラーライズハーモニーのテーマにすごく合ってる曲だなって。
It's an unusually refreshing song. But it fits the theme of "Color Rise Harmony" so well.
ほんとに！そう！うれしいな。こう色づいていくね、このネ景色がすごく綺麗だなっ
Really! Yes! I'm so happy. The scenery coloring like this is so beautiful.
て、甘いましたよ。なんかせれるな。
I got all shy saying that. Why are you giggling?
さあさあさあ、でもね、あの、MCもあんまり時間がないんですけども。
Now then, we don't have much time for MC either.
え、そうなんですか？そうなんですよ、でもせっかく我々MCやらしていただいてるので、やっぱりコールアンドレスポンスしたいですよね？
Eh, is that right? That's right, but since we get to MC, we definitely want to do a call-and-response, right?
したーい！
We do!
ということで、じゃあ、ドリスコリやっていきます？ちょっと待ってください。うちはさっきクリエイターズステージでコールアンドレスポンスやりましたので、うちからやらせていただきたいと。
So, shall we do Doris-kori? Wait a minute. We already did a call-and-response at Creators Stage, so we want to go first.
あ、そうそうそう！見せてくれるんですか？お手本、お手本お願いします！
Ah, that's right! Will you show us? Please show us an example!
それでは皆さん、うちが「うっち、うっち、うちだよ」と言ったらみんなが「狼みおだよー」って言って貰えば大丈夫です。
Alright everyone, when I say, "Uchi, uchi, uchi da yo," you all reply with, "Ookami Mio da yo!"
じゃあいきますよ。うっち、うっち、うちだよ！
Here we go! Uchi, uchi, uchi da yo!
狼みおだよー！お前らが狼みおだ！
Ookami Mio da yo! You guys are Ookami Mio!
うちってことを！よっしゃってことを！うっちうっち！はい！
Saying "Uchi"! Hell yeah! Uchi uchi! Yes!
じゃあ、じゃあこれ、じゃあこれ数できそう？おじゃあ、みおさんいっときます？え、いいんですか？
So, can we do this? Mio, want to go next? Eh, is that okay?
じゃあちょっと今日はね、みんなこの衣装を着てますでしょ？
Well then today, everyone is wearing this outfit, right?
え、今日の日よ、どうかな？って聞いたらみんな、わかるかな？みんなわかるよね？
If I ask, "How is today?" will you all know? Everyone knows, right?
いい感じ、いい感じ。いきますよ！じゃあ、今日のよ、どうかな？
Looking good, looking good. Here we go! So, how is today?
かわいいよー！ありがとうー！
So cute! Thank you!
可愛いよ！可愛いよ！うわ、可愛いよ。
So cute! So cute! Aw, so cute.
じゃあ白上もさ、いつも定番なのはさ、100万回愛してるなんですけども、ちょっと2人には吹雪王国の国民になってもらおうかな？
And Fubuki, my usual staple is "I love you a million times," but I thought I'd make you two become citizens of Fubuki Kingdom!
えー！？そうなんですか？今日もちょっと、そのライブが終わってしまって大変緊張するんですけど、そのライブの気持ちでやらさせてください。
Eh?! Really? Today's live is ending and I'm super nervous, but let me do it with that live energy.
今日、今みんなここにいるみんな、吹雪王国の国民ということで、白上がですね
Today, everyone here right now is a citizen of Fubuki Kingdom, so—
じゃみんなもちょっとポーズやってほしいんですけど。こう右手を胸にやって
Now I want everyone to strike a pose. Put your right hand on your chest like this—
吹雪王国に栄光あれっていう、このポインです。吹雪王国に栄光あれを一緒にやってほしいです。
And say, "Glory to Fubuki Kingdom!" I want us all to do "Glory to Fubuki Kingdom" together!
じゃあみんな構え！はい、構え！いきますよ。吹雪王国に栄光あれー！
Alright everyone, get into position! Ready, set! Glory to Fubuki Kingdom!
いや、気持ちいいな。ありがとうございまーす！
Man, that feels great. Thank you so much!
じゃあ国民会さん、ありがとうございます。すっごいね、一体感あって。というわけでなんやかんやとしておりますと、なんと
Alright, citizens, thank you! Such an amazing sense of unity. And as we were chatting away, what do you know—
え？無料パートがここまで？えー！？
Eh? The free part ends here? What?!
終わっちゃうということなので、よろしければ皆さん、配信で見ている皆さんは概要欄からぜひとも配信チケットご購入していただけると嬉しいです。
It means we're wrapping up, so if you are watching the stream, we would be so happy if you could purchase a streaming ticket via the description box!
あったね
That's right.
楽しんでね！
Have fun!
そしてそしてハッシュタグ「#hololiveFesEXPO25_Days」でもいっぱいポストしてください！
And be sure to post a lot with the hashtag #hololiveFesEXPO25_Days!
いっぱい呟いてね！
Tweet as much as you want!
harmony 重ねた言葉 届け
Harmony — layered words, reach out
たどたどしく 描いては
Clumsily drawing our dreams
ぎこちない と笑っていた
Laughing at how awkward they seemed
未来予想 あの日の続きを見よう
Let’s continue the story we envisioned that day
ということでですね、ではですね、このままみなさんせいっぱい楽しんでいきましょう！
And with that, everyone, let's keep enjoying yourselves to the fullest!
イェーイ！
Yay!
じゃあ今回の最後の挨拶いきますよー、せーの！
Now for our final greeting, ready, set!
必ずハーモニー！
Forever in harmony!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part has ended! Thank you for watching!
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.
無料パートは終了いたしました！ ご視聴ありがとうございました！